...lives here where it build twenty fifteen...pretty excited beer with
Right how you guys doing pretty good so there was an interesting announcement
today that you guys have a little bit of work on could you tell us what
that is...I was pretty excited when I watch
has would say maybe we should use visual studios somewhere else
...you guys in working on how...come about.
Well,...been working on what has become which...code which is an editor
which provides to.
Reach coding...experience and neutrons cross-platform so
you can code wherever you are with the technologies
uone right so what how is...I was interest because my side I thought what
...looks similar to some other things how is it built-in.
So, we didn't start from scratch the first of all there is a history...be work on html
five base tooling and editing experiences kind of four years.
And, we started with an.
Online tools like their lawn which was a labels on national since
...jan monaco which allows
...sites kind of in the browser.
And, this is matured over time and, we basically you're using this technology and
...jan monaco the editor and
...to...we also leveraging at these run-time infrastructure
two-run html five that node and javascript as a
desktop application which is kind of this electron which has...with at michelle from
...which gives us the run-time infrastructure we put our editor on top and then of course
...also...together and he came out quite a different architecture for
...although languages benches to maybe languages like csharp.
Right now this is a go ahead sorry
... the history the editors is quite interesting as well actually
that it's non-transfer...was the first thing that the team produced and.
The first liberals for that editor work in things like one drive or as your
or visual studio online...twelve to but the editor also shifts in the
...twelve so when you bring up that...tools for...explore that is the
...what we call the monochrome and that's the core of
...business your code so it's...over the past four years it's been development
...been battle tested and you know, performances grade handle
very long on media...savior aggressive dog food.
So, when we started development...three-month so for...he started doing all of
the development using our...less painful the beginning but this
has continue it's good to have pain when you're building the...that's giving you paint
right, yeah, that's cool so it seems like you had all of this investment into monaco and
you thought well let's go level two and just make an application that you can run anywhere?
That's interesting so we had we have we still have...on...websites we have monaco
...the browser right and it's actually quite a successful
tool is like three thousand people that use it every month the out whatever
...the wanted-to ...the challenges
with posting tools is the fact that developers have a full.
Toolbox full of things that they use day-in-and-day-out and,
it's very difficult to take...tools and bring them up to the
...right so we looked at you know-how can we make the environment
...run in the cloud more robustwe also looked at should be then go
...cross-platform and bring it to more and more machines so we had the opportunity to take the
technologies running up...the cloud and bring a cross-platform get the benefits of the
...lightweight tooling environment easy access from anywhere but,
it runs...machines...integrates...rest, yeah, that's a pretty cool sort
of I really liked the idea of doing that...it...javascript.
No, actually no we started four years ago did there was
...javascript and...the same time types...emerge
...of diverse early adopters of types...and restarted
gradually adopting more and now weights at all types fifth the
...architectures now multiprocessor architecture because you also want to support csharp
right and for csharp microsoft has this nice...infrastructure...which you don't
...rewriting childless...and the baby leverage...is by a rom
...in...in a separate process and then talking
...through a simple protocol and he factor and in fact
...open-source project has already started doing that which was called open
...and all-new shar
...joint this efforts...some of my team members actually
are kilometers over the...is open-source project then so.
The nice thing is many comes to...services you can write them into language you
walk right...want to a python service you can write
...the brain of the service entice them and we
...through the...from our...javascript
...service is there a way to sort of build those plug-in...that's something we have to wait for your
team-building so we work on and extensibility
infrastructure but we decided snot mature yet not radiate right and we take
that serious nobody comes to api and things like that you don't...break.
And, once you have open the door...cannot just them change
...all of everything right so that's...set for the preview that you
...able to date there is no extension infrastructure alka so
the behind-the-scene people cedar is a...fold and stuff like that but we
don't it's not public right so it's very nice especially the
architectures that if you want to extended another language
services runs out of process it's not like you have to fit into the mold that we've defined you
can...in your language the way you want reddit and then all we ask is, you know,
the protocol is matched you can
...whatever did you want...you don't have to get a frameworks...is the box that you have to
live in you can work that you...work...the way you want to work the
...want to...still integrate I think the cool thing is that since it's written javascript,
javascript is such a forgiving language when it comes to doing stuff.
Is that good
or bad I don't know I have my own opinion about that
...five-foot comes around reversal get a sites around all right we have some questions coming
in are there any...entire bs to os x and linux I think this question sort of
...direct the fact that visual studio code is not
...visual studio it is not visual...no plans it like
reporting effort of visual studio to...it's not even clear that you can...visual
studios a great example of all the technology...we shipped over the years uses a holtz on but,
really what we want to do is think about taking the what we
...with the...the key features of visual studio and bringing
them cross-platform so you get the great intelligence experience
...coding experience powered by roslyn ...get a great debugging experience
...by the debugging engine of visual studio...will bring over the key pieces that
makes sense bring over it and...tools...set of thing hey we're going to go port this thing
...ten years later we would have a fort worth and
...were so it's not the intent that visual
studio code is full visual studio...nine-out-of-ten at all we wanted
to under spectrum right if you have a spectrum from editors undecided that knows
...and aidid that gives you all can basal services you want to be close to the editor right but
...want...things speech and?
Deeper development to make you productive like that's why
...say debugging we'd like to have index.
And, whenever we do that we like to esri said look into can be share code we
...studio...a good example debugging without something we can share code and this will
have more and more with time so it's not the whole visual studio but some dots from visual studio run
...share across the
in the family right you might be a good family member and share lots of yeses from the
...if you were to say okay visual, visual studio code is
...editor...what would be the losses that
...adding just the standard...I would say those things...that reach language
...and debugging and that...integration
...control integration what makes this in a...in a little buddy
...you code right what you do you make...you want to
...your code you...you check the main when I look at what you...that...elope activities
...have...there but not much more ok so there's a very clear vision of what
of what's going to be in there and what's not because about...the...edit compiled debug
...want that to be in there if...things that you need to do outside that then
...should integrate well with other tools creative through working with the file system or are,
you know, through a command-line and command-line
...out those ways to integrate other tools but not try to put everything
...I'd like that there's a specific vision so that if someone comes and says
well why can't I do as well as?
It's good to have an answer like that or...some more questions can will
this editor replaced our shell isd.
The goal is like any...editor today supports many languages but
with different level of...right so today be support our shell at the same
...coloring level which is the basic level only and if you look at dicey right it gives you entirely sense
and things like that which we don't get too but I think over time you want to get as many
...possible to the happy level of in tallies sentence
...references refactoring anything else you
...the...and it's for us of time thing right now we have
...it seems three levels
right basic coloring syntax coloring bracket matching and
...indenting that's the lowest-level which is support for many
languages which make very easy to do...level...is when it comes hard...I go
to definition and levels three is really kind of refactoring and right now we
...phony csharp
...that levels three and javascript html.
Css less they are at the level to be giving palace so we have
and est behind-the-scenes to understand the code more than text right that's why it's...code
...school so but eventually we're going to have
a system where if you have language food when you want to make sure you have support language
...that's something that will be able to add ourselves with...something we had...note we will work on extension
...connection adding a new language is...of the interesting scenarios
...all right question here...to bubble platforms such as android ios
...windows...that's an interesting question because this...javascript.
You can run an visual studio monaco on these devices right
you'd even right that we...on and android template we did...
So, there are scenarios...makes sense but for what we have free might be code
...kind of seven by twenty-four coding righty it's not the top
scenario...we talked about earlier...they were trying to integrate with...this tool...
I don't have that...on your phone.
...that makes it, you know,...interesting scenario our next question what are the dependencies
two-run visual studio code...today the.
So, depending on what is that you want to write...rate straight
...out-of-the-box on linux you don't have any dependencies if you want
to know development and...debugging
...hp dot net developments today you need to have more mono...
zero dot one installed on the linux box and on the site and
on...net site...very simple.
...of scripts you can run to get that all installed
onto linux machine dot net so the next question is what about
rich...support I think that goes a little bit towards...talking about...three levels right now if
...support is at the lowest-level...is...a single...deeper language
understand so we can't wait till the open-door for extensibility and then of
course people can add that and can help us to go one level got
...you going to integrate cplus-plus and tellers sense into bs code that's an interesting question
...roslyn visit work in the cplus-plus area now...is the managed code visual
the behind and csharp so it's interesting right for csharp
for cplus-plus there's a one of these and language changing similar offline...on
...right and of course it would be nice scenario to use clang as this out of process
...tocs well protocol and that's how you get that but again I guess we
have to make first this the extension stores able that we can
you might orders to help us on that but the...goes in this direction right you want to
leverages language engines and for cplus-plus there is a good one out there
so the next question can this compile the apps
...reference I download try to compile my store app?
The question is there like...compile
...certain kind of absent you're like you shouldn't really be working on inside...visual studio
code or is it really just editor what's the bloop look like for someone that's doing,
for example, storehouse so for perhaps like this there's this to create?
An enormous number of different types of projects...number of different
dependencies and things that only run install on windows itself so it's challenge you say,
yeah, you could open up any project in visual studio code on linux
...is there's a lot of fundamental pieces that aren't there so what we have today is support for
asp dot net the five applications...and we have support
for...csharp applications and,
that's the scope of what we...for manage code...
cross-platform I see...that's interesting I mean it's good to know the boundary right?
On windows its mean...code runs cross-platform also runs...windows if you got
...store app...got all the tools installed visual studio you can certainly go
to the consul on windows and run microsoft build
...your application and do all that but you're not going to get
...built-in support in the code environment for
those project types now I guess it's good to know?
What it's for and what that's good a good of demarcation
...from our will you support sl and cs projects?
So, this actually the whole...for csharp...and only show
up-to-date supports solution and cs proj files iness somewhat constrained
...because...with...solution project systems are open-ended
...support them all that are scenarios says so you can
...solution file which only references...and if they're not too many customizations on the
...can...not hundred-forty...I think you...back to your point like
...was very clear what is...what is
...acinet...five projects are support...yes skeptic.
And, then folder based html javascript node
based applications where there is no project system that's involved ...also say types your product
...has a ts...file which is kind of like a project descriptor and
we support that as well okay but for mans...
...but, the newest version yes got
...question...will there be act...six language and types script debugging
...tab skip debugging support was that close to make
it preview basically means you have to support source maps right and you had some
...very close so that.
You will make...mature and...make...able in one of a next iteration cl
Revert internally in...short...three experience
and the plant also continued that and make...stuff of able india's is read
...sizing is will be one of the next brains that we can
...label all right this is an interesting question one was asked earlier and I wanted
to see your take on it will visual studio code be open-source.
...my answer is some of it is already opensource right views
...on the...use only shop which is opensource which is this
...because opensource we use...service which is open-source so we build on many
...things which you actually also contributed to now the whole the
...the demonic creative and things like that that's what the will discuss in
the next month what makes sense...how we can...back
to the community but is a discussions you having right so...got is already pretty much
open-source although you sort of...all of these pieces and build the
...top right and also be use open-source underneath this right there is
...electron framework from get-tough that allows views...than html.
At five that's already multi-use and also what the conned
...pull requests how you do decibels
...these days that's really cool so very ultimately wealthy architecture identity one
...extensibility story and once you have that then I think...sense
...a discussion what makes sense opensource and whatnot because...preview mode there's still some baking media
up the...from wesley...plans for us six-day as support of we already there's a
flag...the dispersion...what it looks like it only supports the sthree
...we already talked about that this close right,...it's all right daniel
are you planning...wider range of programming language in terms of highlighting and syntax...give us a
reminder of the three levels again for those of maybe urges to...so the leveled the base level is right you
get coloring color-coded brackets and yet prank matching
...indenting that's the one which we have a broad spectrum what is it thirty language
...thirty, thirty languages and we also leverage again
open-source technology for the like...can consume
text make bundles golly languages which has.
Happened is community and then...above is really kind of you...to give
in telly sentence and go-to definition and understand multi files
...have to go up understanding more than one files writing get...level two
and level top-level...refactoring so the nirvana is all languages odd
levels three buy that thing this will...got to build them up as you go with...with
the so what are the level three languages that are in...already type skip and csharp got
mark is there is there plan a plan for cplus-plus support for linux intelligence
...like we did talk about that right it's definitely a possibility
that something that you're looking seamus interesting...I...language protocol if you look at
the protocol itself it's not very language specific but if you can considering
telly sense...needs note at this text position I need
...to proposal right yahoo at the protocol levels almost language neutral
of course the language server has all the brain...the computation but the protocol
...really...of...exactly and that's why we hope we will
...should happen at some point once you have the
...story red dot is...fs support...upcoming.
Well, so,...basic level today you know,...support get source
control so you can push and pull...get...online I guess the question is to
fs to fast-food...studio online the ask questions service the
...positive control it is honor backlog but,
we went with get the first we think about, you know,
building asp net web applications cross-platform get was.
Popular source code controls the amount of support for so adults
...and, css supports the command-line and code is open to command-line say can use the
command-line to do you odf source code operations you don't get the nice the
...tool...is they're going to be is there because we talked a lot about extensions in
the future for language support to get left languages up to level three is they're going to
be extensibility on the providers for ...we already
...feature requests...want...they want to have auto-detects I think this is part of
...story not...very days I think language extensions more important we have to see
...the backlog...it so ...michael does bs code support new get.
I think there's I think we're getting to like a common like does it do this
...that the answer is almost invariably yes if you can do in the command-line
yes and that's how it works today so if you're using
...pfive everything comes out as
movie packages so from the tool we can read in you know, commands for is
...ninety-five plus we also have, you know, ...update dn you restore which...go and
...down all the packages from you get there's nothing in the tool itself that, you know, this out all the
package we don't think that we should put that in the tool it's a good command-line
tool we do...in project jason which is kind of the project container file for
...net pfive applications is a list of dependencies that are in their of obvious assemblies
...consuming your app we have a great...sense experience...control space
...query the new get repository ballistic everything version numbers and all that and
we'll talk to go and restore all those packages so in that core sort of
edit compile loop let you go in pull down the right packages kick-off
...the store and, go from there, yeah, so,
it sounds like if you're targeting like we're building
...dot net five right is that what deserves every five of five applicants
based net totally were in there and, I think it's because you're if you're making
of work on several different platforms you need to have sort of an
environment that supports platform that's why you gotta use
mono in some cases on the other all right so a...leo's will there be a clearer
path that will lead third-party tools into integrations into visual studio code
this extension story right that we're working on?
Big...all right so here's a long one from linux or hp ux
is it possible to commit code to via so from visual studio code can-you connected to
...social use other tools to...repository so first of all know our code right now
...code is hosting media and you have team members they work from linux...work
...and they all commit go
repositories so yes you can do that of course...we don't support to connect
...so-you clone it and then once have clone did you berkeley decode anyone
...studio code cbs...that's our day-to-day work actually
...what work with unity replacing their model-based id
...guys...that it seems like.
If you're just editing the file it should work...it csharp
...language services if it can ping rosalyn it should work
...approaching metadata
...challenge right we need to know limit more about how you build your sources that's
We use these...fully support asp next projects this project
...metadata about any support...of solutions yes but in the
end if you're just looking for a really good code
text editor with syntax highlighting we have support for thirty so
...and if you're just editing tax it's going to be great okay plus
...integration...code anyone...get
...help perfect what's the difference between this...the...out this is going to
bring...to relief a little bit more what you've actually done with right so as I said only
...kind of...server that...ui
talks too so it's a part of it right so it's become csharp support
...is that engine the brain that gives
us the intelligence to give you entirely sense for csharp.
So, it's actually part of the...product...code consumes
...which in turn consumes roslyn...
ok perfect are there any plans for all we talked about...
yes I because plug-in supports going thought about it there's thoughts on that going forward
...visual studio...use with the same...installed was...on math?
This depends...what's the version model that do need to have
...so, there's, there's a couple of levels of things and,...just kind of
the state of as these projects move forward for
...dot net be five support you need mono four-point-zero point one
and hp dot net pfive setup has a home...
Or sexes a home brew...formula which will go and pull that down...not doing acinet the
pfive applications you don't need model for one if you
...debugging we need models for ten
Twelve.
I mean no, three that what's him...job hand-eye thing I think three up
...a question like do you need mono at all do text
...language service...romano to do know debugging
any need mono to do asp dot net pfive apps so to finish up where
could people go right now to download...learn more about visual
...I think I have the website up here...I was so excited about code that
...see the...and how long does it take you I think I did live it took me like
sixty to ninety seconds it was go-fast usually I'm like, you know,
I'm installing something substantial I'm going to go get something to drink but
this was just really, really fast so what are you most excited about this?
Well, so, far...we...of media...number-one heckman used in...with us
...exciting right so it is not something that you do that much and
...feedback is very that you get some appreciation
I'm excited about it hopefully you guys are excited about it please take a download of it
...to minutes doing it and we're out...see you next time.